{
  "reference_number": "1560",
  "clauses": [
    {
      "question": "1. What process should the Government use to set a new emissions reduction target in legislation?",
      "question_index": 0,
      "answer": "The Government sets a 2050 target in legislation now",
      "answer_index": 0,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "2. If the Government sets a 2050 target now, which is the best target for New Zealand?",
      "question_index": 1,
      "answer": "Net Zero Emissions - Net zero emissions across all greenhouse gases by 2050",
      "answer_index": 1,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "3. How should New Zealand meet its targets?",
      "question_index": 2,
      "answer": "Domestic emissions reductions only (including from new forest planting)",
      "answer_index": 7,
      "notes": "It's more effective to invest in domestic emissions reductions only in order to affect the necessairy domestic action and change.\n\n International carbon units are just a paper excercise."
    },
    {
      "question": "4. Should the Zero Carbon Bill allow the 2050 target to be revised if circumstances change?",
      "question_index": 3,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "Only in case of sudden, unexpected circumstances or when circumstances are worse than expected; as well as for new international\n treaty or agreement obligations but not for political reasons. (See Q 7)"
    },
    {
      "question": "5. The Government proposes that three emissions budgets of five years each (i.e. covering the next 15 years) be in place at any given time. Do you agree with this proposal?",
      "question_index": 15,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "6. Should the Government be able to alter the last emissions budget (i.e. furthest into the future)?",
      "question_index": 4,
      "answer": "No - emissions budgets should not be able to be changed",
      "answer_index": 9,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "7. Should the Government have the ability to review and adjust the second emissions budget within a specific range under exceptional circumstances? See p36 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 5,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "In case of sudden, unexpected circumstances or when circumstances are worse than expected; as well as for new international\n\n treaty or agreement obligations but not for political reasons or gains."
    },
    {
      "question": "8. Do you agree with the considerations we propose that the Government and the Climate Change Commission take into account when advising on and setting budgets? See p44 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 6,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "9. Should the Zero Carbon Bill require Governments to set out plans within a certain timeframe to achieve the emissions budgets?",
      "question_index": 7,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "10. What are the most important issues for the Government to consider in setting plans to meet budgets? For example, who do we need to work with, what else needs to be considered?",
      "question_index": 8,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "Most updated scientific data, evidence-based policy initiatives as well as innovation need to be considered. It's critical that plans for\nincreasing the number of trees and forestry activities adopt a diverse approach. The mono-culture of Pinus Radiata is risky,\n\nunsustainable and undesirable. There is too much wastage from current logging practices and neighbours down streams suffer the\nconsequences. Regional councils also seem to be reluctant to prosecute breaches under the RMS. There needs to be more\n\nregulation to enforce sustainable logging practises, whereby clear felling and erosion is reduced as well as better protection of\nwaterways. Forestry isn't really economically viable for many farmers at the moment and they will be reluctant to switch to this landuse\n\nwithout incentives. Without any structural change to the forestry industry, landwoners are currently unlikely to receive any worthwhile\nprice increases as log prices increase. Landowners and regions should receive Government support to develop small-scale,\nspecialised diverse, woodlots and local industries to produce high-quality wood products."
    },
    {
      "question": "11. The Government has proposed that the Climate Change Commission advises on and monitors New Zealand's progress towards its goals. Do you agree with these functions? See p42 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 9,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "Advise Government and hold Government to account"
    },
    {
      "question": "12. What role do you think the Climate Change Commission should have in relation to the New Zealand Emissions Trading Scheme (NZ ETS)?",
      "question_index": 10,
      "answer": "Makes decisions itself in respect of the number of units available in the NZ ETS",
      "answer_index": 10,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "13. The Government has proposed that Climate Change Commissioners need to have a range of essential and desirable expertise. Do you agree with the proposed expertise? See p45 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 11,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "Politically neutral and not appointed by the Government of the day."
    },
    {
      "question": "14. Do you think the Zero Carbon Bill should cover adapting to climate change?",
      "question_index": 12,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "15. The Government has proposed a number of new functions to help us adapt to climate change. Do you agree with the proposed functions? See p47 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 13,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "16. Should we explore setting up a targeted adaptation reporting power that could see some organisations share information on their exposure to climate change risks?",
      "question_index": 14,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "Reporting would pose too much administrative burden. Maybe it could be considered at a later date when there is a lack of progress."
    },
    {
      "question": "Do you have any other comments you'd like to make?",
      "question_index": 16,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "Not sure whether a Climate Change Commission will be able to leverage the desirable change. It just seems to be another advice-\ngiving body. Please withold my name and contact details from any publications or info release."
    }
  ]
}
